Hello everyone, a very warm welcome to all of you.
You are watching You The Real, I am your
own personal advisor Amitraj Sharma. The credit for today's
video goes to Sonu Rajput's
comment. Sonu ji,
thank you very much for your comment. Many thanks. If you
all want to know about Aditya Bedla Sun Life Insurance
Company Limited's Fixed Income Plus Plan,
then check the description of today's video.
You will get the
video link of this plan, which will
save your time. As you all know
that every video on the channel
comes according to your suggestions, questions and comments.
Therefore, stay connected with us so that
you keep getting information about new videos.
For that, like and share the video
and do not forget to subscribe to the channel.
In today's video, we are going to learn about Aditya Bedla Sun Life
Insurance Company Limited's Salary Term
Plan. This
plan is a non-linked non-participating
life individual pure risk premium
plan. Now, if we understand this line in our own words, then the
premium that we will
pay to the insurance company here will be based on our age,
sum assured and policy term.  On a base basis, the
insurance company is not going to invest that premium in equity
or stocks in the market.
Non-participating
means that the
bonus announced every year at the end of the financial year by the
insurance company is
also not applicable in this policy.
Now, pure premium means
here that on the basis of the premium we are
paying to the insurance company, we are
given a sum assured i.e. life cover,
which we get in case of our death or in case of our
illness, or it is
given to our nominee. Okay,
yes, in case of illness, in
case of death, our nominee gets it. Now,
before moving ahead, let us understand the eligibility criteria of the salary term plan. The
age limit for taking this plan is from
21 years to 55 years and the
maturity age limit is from 31
years to 70 years, that is,
you will be able to remain under the cover in the plan only till the maximum age of 70 years
in case of limited pay in premium payment term.  There are premium payment term options of 5 years, 7 years, 10 years, 12 years,
15 years and 20 years.
In Limited Pay, the
minimum policy term will be
5 years. If you
add 5 years to the premium payment term, then the
positive term becomes 10 years. Regular Pay means the
premium payment term will be for the same number of years as the policy term. In case of the minimum policy term, the minimum
policy term is 10 years. The maximum is
49 years, i.e., 49 years. The
minimum sum assured limit is ₹
lakh. The maximum sum assured limit depends on
how much the insurance company approves you as per your eligibility criteria, i.e., as per its underwriting rules and regulations. The
premium in the plan will depend on
your age, policy term, sum, short plan
option. Premium payment term and policy
term are also included in this,
now we will talk about the salary
of Aditya Birla Sunlife Insurance Company Limited.
Regarding the main benefit of the term plan, if it is a
term plan then one thing
is clear that it will have death benefit which is the main one
which we know that in case of death the nominee gets the
claim, the second benefit is terminal
illness cover which is inbuilt, that is
a disease which at least two medical
practitioners have professionally told
that the life assured has been
diagnosed with and that disease can cause
death of the life assured in the next six months,
then in such a case 50% of the sum assured that you have taken the cover will be paid to
you immediately
in case of terminal illness and
all future premiums will be waived
and the policy will continue i.e. if there is
a disease due to which you may
die in the next six months and this has been
told by two medical practitioners then only you will
get the right and the cover of terminal illness will be
under the cover only till your maximum age of 70 years, that is, it
is available only if it happens till this age and the
limit of cover for terminal illness is Rs. 2 crore
What is the minimum limit kept at
50% of your sum assured? Okay, so this thing is
clear here. In case of terminal illness,
if it happens later, then the
balance sum assured which is 50% of the basic sum
assured is paid to the nominee. The
second benefit is the accelerated
critical illness benefit. This benefit is also
covered up to a maximum age of 70 years only. To
calculate its term,
you will subtract your age from 70 years
and the waiting period for accelerated critical illness is
90 days. The
sum amount limit for accelerated critical illness is
from ₹ lakh to a
maximum of 50% of your basic sum assured or
50 lakh, that is, what is the maximum limit,
50 lakh. Now, there are 42
critical illnesses listed under this, their names are
on your screen, if you want to know all their
details  If you want to know about the terms and conditions, then
for that you will have to read its PDF, the
link of which is given in the description of the video. There are
four different options in this plan. The
first is the life cover option. The second is the life cover
with return of premium option which is
called ROP. The third is the fixed income cover
option. The fourth is the increasing income cover option.
Okay, now there are four options, so obviously all the four
options are different from each other
and the conditions will also be slightly different. That is why
in today's video we will share with you only the information about option number one and
option number two.
With the example, the main
benefits will remain the same as those told to you.
So here we take the example of the life cover option i.e. option number one of Aditya Birla Sun
Life Insurance Salary Term Plan. Let us
assume that Mr. A
is 35 years old and is
taking a positive term of 30 years. He has taken a term of 30 years only.
He has chosen the premium payment
term i.e. regular pay option here. He has decided the sum
assured here of ₹1 crore, so annually
They will pay a premium of ₹1,400 and
you get to see the terminal illness cover with all the options in it.
Now let us assume that Mr. A gets himself
diagnosed after completion of 15 years of the policy
and he comes to know that he has a
terminal illness and this is
told by two medical practitioners due to which
he may die in the next six months. In
such a situation, the benefit of the terminal illness
cover, 50% of the basic sum assured,
which will amount to ₹1 lakh, will be paid by the
company to Mr. A. After that,
all future premiums will be waived, that is,
no premium will have to be paid for the next 15 years. If the lady
survives for that long
after terminal illness, then otherwise,
whenever she dies after the 15th year, then
50% of the base sum assured, which has
become 50 lakh, the balance amount will be
given to the nominee. The policy will be closed
if the policyholder  If death occurs due to
accident
or any other reason and not due to death, then the normal sum of ₹ crore will be
given to the nominee as a claim and the
policy will be closed. Now, let us
understand the example of life cover option of Salary Term Plan of Aditya Billa Sunlife Insurance Company Limited with Accelerated Critical Illness Benefit. We are taking the same example:
Age 35 years, Policy term of 30 years,
Premium payment term of 30 years.
What Shrimani did here was that he added Accelerated Critical
Illness Benefit cover of 25 lakhs.
Right, in this case, the life cover becomes
₹ lakhs. The total base sum
becomes ₹ crores. So, the
premium to be paid for Accelerated Critical Illness Cover is
₹ 14125 and the
life cover premium to be paid is ₹
13400, that is, the annual premium.  On
adding that ₹2500000 Accelerated Critical Illness Benefit, your premium
increases here. The amount of increase will depend on the
policy term you have taken,
your understanding of the cover, and the amount of Accelerated
Critical Benefit cover you are taking. Let
us assume that after the 16th year of the policy, Mr. A has developed
any one of the 42 listed critical illnesses, in
such a case,
Mr. A will be
given ₹1 lakh as Accelerated Critical Illness Benefit cover.
After that, the
policy will continue with the base life cover of ₹1 lakh
and an annual premium of ₹10 will have to be paid in
future. That means,
if there is a death in future, the nominee will get ₹1 lakh
and the policy will be discontinued. You have to pay attention to
this thing in this case, the premium is not waived.
Okay,
now let us talk about the second option, Life
Cover with Return of Premium.  The
terminal benefit of the option will work in the same way
as told to you, no extra premium has to be
paid. Okay, if you
add the accelerated critical benefit, then
extra premium will be paid. So this is the return of
premium option. Life cover, which is option
number two, is taking the same example. We are taking the same sum assured,
but the annual
premium of ₹2500000 will become
₹105000, which will be returned to them at the
end of the 30th year of the policy i.e. on maturity.
And if they
die during the policy term, then their nominee can get the
base sum assured of ₹1 crore as a
claim. Okay, so we
saw here that when we were taking the life cover option, i.e.
option number one, age of 35 years,
policy term of 30 years, premium payment of 30 years,
we were taking a term sum assured of ₹1 lakh.
So, for the life cover option, our
premium that was going here was going here.
₹1,400 is fine but when we
chose the life cover with return of premium option, then why ₹5,000,000
because we just want a return of
premium back on maturity.
Now suppose that the extra
₹1,100,000 that you
invest in any mutual fund annually, then
in 30 years you will be able to earn ₹10 lakh. If
you continue investing ₹1,000,000 annually and
suppose the rate of return from time to time is 8%, then you get
between 10 and 15%.
So when the 30 years of the policy are
completing, if the RE is also 8%, then
this amount comes to around 22,460, which is what
you can get. So, for this reason, I
say that the return of premium does
not seem right to me personally. Everyone else has
their own different choices. Okay, if
you have any  If you have any confusion, please
ask in the comment section. Now we will share with
you the details of the next two options with you in the next video
with examples.
Thank you very much for watching the video till the end. Many thanks and gratitude. Understand one thing yourself and
explain it to others also that insurance is
a protection. Protection is never taken incomplete.
If the information in the video is
clear, then please like and share the video. Stay
connected with us by subscribing to the channel and take care of yourself. Thank you
very much and thank you very much.